ROBINSON ROA

Phone: +58 412-560-0476

Email: roa.robinson97@gmail.com

LinkedIn: <u>robinson-roa</u> **GitHub:** <u>RoaRobinson97</u>

Location: Caracas, Venezuela, 1040

Software Engineer

SUMMARY

Seasoned Software Engineer with six years of expertise, specializing in system design, business modeling and full-stack development. Strong problem-solving skills and a deep understanding of software architecture. Led the pioneering development team at Poly186 Al DAO, successfully steering projects to advanced stages.

KEY ACCOMPLISHMENTS

- Successfully structured and managed Development and Product departments at Poly186. Developed streamlined workflows, which increased project delivery efficiency by 50%.
- Played a pivotal role in startup's progression from inception to full-scale development and production, overseeing the **shift from initial ideas to a thriving operational phase.**
- Led the design, development, and successful launch of a Flutter-based mobile app for Fence: Social Distance. Collaborated with the Product Owner to define requirements and deliver a user-friendly app promoting social distancing. (May 2020 – Jun 2020)

WORK EXPERIENCE

Chief Technology and Product Officer / Poly186

Sep 2021 – Present / United States

- **Established and managed** the Development and Product departments, implementing and documenting streamlined workflows that resulted in a 50% increase in project delivery efficiency.
- Managed a team 4 developer and 3 designers, working cross- functionally on different products and projects (NFT minting, wallet tied to account, crypto purchase), expending 50% of time coding.
- **Conducted scrum meetings,** code reviews and provided constructive feedback to ensure codebase quality, tracking progress of the teams.
- Carried modernization of previous source code, **documenting** old and new code bases.
- Introduced and oversaw automated testing and CI/CD.

Full-Stack Developer / Avybe

Jan 2021 - Jun 2021 / Canada

- Collaborated within a fast-paced, distributed team, making significant contributions to the development of new features for a video streaming platform.
- Implemented file storage using AWS S3.
- **Designed and developed** new use cases and business flows, developing innovative features across backend (Django), frontend (React Native), and database (PostgreSQL).

Staff Developer / OfficeNinjas

Sep 2019 - Dec 2020 / United States

- I specialized in Zapier, using JavaScript to **integrate third-party apps**, which significantly enhanced productivity in an online distributed environment.
- I was responsible for **designing and testing** email/newsletter templates in ActiveCampaign, utilizing HTML and CSS.

Business Analyst and Full-Stack Developer (Early Career Experience)

- Jun 2019 Aug 2019, Fondo de Valores Inmobiliarios, Venezuela: I collaborated within a team to streamline development for a BonitaSoft-based solution. Optimized BPM flows, enhanced reporting efficiency using JasperReports, and contributed to frontend improvements with Angular. Additionally, managed databases on Microsoft SQL Server.
- May 2018 May 2019, Freelancer: Designed databases using MySQL Workbench, created BPMN diagrams, and proficiently handled SQL queries, procedures, and triggers to enhance data management and system functionality.

PERSONAL SKILLS

- Communication
- Teamwork
- Problem solving
- Attention to detail
- Critical Thinking
- Proactive
- Project Management

LANGUAGES

Spanish – **Native** English – **C2**

TECHNICAL SKILLS

React/React Native, Flutter, Node.js, Django, SQL, JavaScript, Python, Dart, Java, Next.js, GO, HTML, CSS, SCSS, Golang, Material UI, Tailwind, Bootstrap, PostgreSQL, MySQL, Microsoft SQL Server, Oracle Database, Firebase, MongoDB, AWS, Azure, GitHub Actions, Docker, Rest API, GraphQL, Ether.js, BonitaSoft, JasperReports.

EDUCATION

BACHELOR OF COMPUTER SCIENCE (92% Completed)

July 2024 / Universidad Central de Venezuela / Caracas, Venezuela

CERTIFICATIONS

<u>WEB DEVELOPMENT WITH REACT</u> – Coursera <u>MOBILE DEVELOPMENT WITH REACT NATIVE</u> – Coursera <u>MOBILE DEVELOPMENT WITH FLUTTER</u> – Udemy